[Music]
hi and welcome back to the cold ridden
five dollar shake today we're gonna make
haagen-dazs irish cream brownie
it's all a bit nasally the daughter's
gone to nursery and she's bringing a
whole load of germs back so
beautiful
so what is irish cream brownie it is an
irish cream ice cream with rich
chocolate brownies and a decadent
chocolate fudge swirl a lot of people
have problems making
irish cream ice cream because apparently
you can't get a decent amount of flavor
in but
i disagree anyway if you want to see how
we do it stick around and we'll show you
[Music]
we're going to start with the base so
put your milk your sugars which has got
the stabilizer in it mixed in well your
egg yolks and skim milk powder into a
pan and gently heat up to 82 degrees c
that's to make sure your eggs are cooked
doing the custard this way will stop the
need to temper them in a more
traditional way and it is much safer and
easier to do
once that's up to temperature remove it
from the heat and put in a container
then add in your cream your vanilla bean
paste and finally your irish cream i'm
using bailey's here
give it a quick stir and then bury it
under a rainbow i mean put it in a
fridge for a few hours
while the base is in the fridge chilling
let's make the fudge so for this put
your milk your sugars and butter in a
pan and heat it up until everything is
melted then add in your cocoa powder and
stir it in well bringing it up to a
decent boil and then turning it off
finally add in your vanilla extract and
store it in a container in the fridge
for later
[Music]
when the base is fully chilled turn it
in your machine
in my lilo 50 30 this took 12 minutes
for the full 1.2 litres of final product
to churn
but your machine could take anywhere
between
10 to 30 minutes
whilst the ice cream is churning chop up
your brownies and keep them in the
freezer until the loading phase
finally
once everything is ready get your fudge
sauce get your chopped brownies and
start loading up your tubs by layering
each one in until it's full then put it
in the freezer for a few hours until
we're ready to try
do
[Music]
check out that tub
now i don't know who this is it's
probably meant to be me drinking the
entire bottle of bailey's under a tree
but why would you not it's pretty early
in the morning no better time to have
some alcoholic ice cream
i'm going to dish them up put it in a
bowl and we'll see what it looks like
[Music]
and there we go
i mean i can smell the bailey's coming
off of it but you can see you've got
loads of different things going on
you've got the fudge ripple going
through there you've got your brownies
that smell of bailey's coming through
i'm gonna try some of this
[Music]
i mean if you go short on the actual
irish cream you're never going to taste
it it's not the strongest of alcohols
out there bailey's is i think 17
so you have to add quite a bit but by
adding quite a bit you're actually
introducing a lot of water as well so
you need to account for that water
somehow
so this recipe accounts for that by the
addition of the skim milk powders the
stabilizers
they absorb that excess water so you get
a really nice creamy texture and that's
what you got here you've got a creamy
ice cream luxurious bailey's taste to it
that fudge sauce is really nice strong
cocoa flavor to that and those brownies
real nice chew to them they don't
disappear like some brownies do a really
nice chewy kind of brownie this is a
really nice combo and i know it's a
popular one for the haagen-dazs fans out
there so
definitely give this one a try if you're
into this whole flavor
anyway i hope you enjoyed the video even
though i have a stinking cold
it probably tastes even stronger without
the cold so maybe i'll just i would say
i'll not eat it all and
try it again when the cold goes but
that's just not gonna happen i'm gonna
eat this all tonight you know that
anyway thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like and subscribe and
we'll see you next week
[Music]